const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During translation, the initiation codon of mRNA attaches to the ribosome at which site?","answers":[{"option":"E site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"A site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"P site of 30S subunit","bool":true},{"option":"A site of 50S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"E site of 50S subunit","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for releasing DNA supercoils?","answers":[{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Single strand DNA","bool":false},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":true},{"option":"DNA ligase","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following cells is not a component of connective tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Chondrocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Histiocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblast","bool":false},{"option":"Goblet cell","bool":true},{"option":"Adipocyte","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A radiologist noticed a fracture of a bone that connects the axial skeleton with the appendicular skeleton on an X-ray. What is the regional classification of the fractured bone?","answers":[{"option":"Membranous","bool":false},{"option":"Cancellous","bool":false},{"option":"Compact","bool":false},{"option":"Appendicular","bool":true},{"option":"Cartilaginous","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 65-year-old female came to the emergency with a hip bone fracture due to slipping on a wet floor. An X-ray revealed she has osteoporosis, which has weakened her bones to a point where they can easily break. Which type of bone is fractured?","answers":[{"option":"Short","bool":false},{"option":"Flat","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular","bool":true},{"option":"Sesamoid","bool":false},{"option":"Long","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 21-year-old medical student decides to take a nap after having his lunch. Which of the following nervous systems is activated?","answers":[{"option":"Peripheral","bool":false},{"option":"Somatic","bool":false},{"option":"Parasympathetic","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Within the cell, DNA is in the nucleus. Which other structure within the cell organelles listed below also contains DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondria","bool":true},{"option":"Peroxisome","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 32-year-old female suffering from lifelong atopic eczema comes to her dermatologist with a rash on her hand, which appeared after direct contact with dish soap. She has a history of rash from wearing certain clothing and jewelry. Which layer of skin is found only in thick skin?","answers":[{"option":"Stratum granulosum","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum lucidum","bool":true},{"option":"Stratum spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum corneum","bool":false},{"option":"Stratum germinativum","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A patient comes to an emergency with a patellar fracture due to an automobile accident. An X-ray confirmed several small fragments of the patella, and the knee is in a semi-flexed position. Which type of bone is fractured?","answers":[{"option":"Long","bool":false},{"option":"Flat","bool":false},{"option":"Short","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular","bool":false},{"option":"Sesamoid","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 20-day-old neonate was diagnosed with chronic diarrhea. The consultant explained to the resident that this was due to the defect in the surface modification of the epithelial lining of the small intestine leading to severe diarrhea and malnutrition. Which of the following is defective in the above case?","answers":[{"option":"Sterocilia","bool":false},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Microvilli","bool":true},{"option":"Villi","bool":false},{"option":"Flagella","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During a histology lecture, the professor discussed about function of epithelium that allows the rapid exchange of gases, active transport by pinocytosis and facilitates movement of viscera and secretions of biologically active substances. Which of the following epithelium types is being described above?","answers":[{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":true},{"option":"Transitional","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Urine is confined to the urinary bladder due to the cell junctions that connect the cell to the urinary bladder. These junctions form a barrier that prevents the exchange of ions and solutes between blood and urine. What is the likely identity of these junctions?","answers":[{"option":"Tight junction","bool":true},{"option":"Desmosome","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junction","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Hemidesmosome","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A researcher is investigating the protein utilized by hemidesmosomes to form an attachment to the extracellular matrix. Which of the following proteins is the researcher investigating?","answers":[{"option":"Desmoplakin","bool":false},{"option":"Desmoglein","bool":false},{"option":"Integrins","bool":true},{"option":"Cadherins","bool":false},{"option":"Desmocollin","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A histopathologist is observing a slide of muscular tissue under a microscope showing striations and peripherally located multiple nuclei. \r\nWhich of the following triads is a feature of this tissue?","answers":[{"option":"2 T-tubules and 1 sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"2 T-tubules","bool":false},{"option":"3 sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"1 T-tubule and 2 sarcoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"3 T-tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Under microscope examination, a single layer of tall cells is found resting on the basement membrane. The height of the cell is greater as compared to its thickness with basally placed nuclei. Which of the following tissues is being observed?","answers":[{"option":"Alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal tract (from stomach to rectum)","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs results in phocomelia in case of its exposure during development?","answers":[{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycoside","bool":false},{"option":"Thalidomide","bool":true},{"option":"Sulphonamide","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During development, which of the following has totipotent cells?","answers":[{"option":"Outer cell mass","bool":false},{"option":"Zygote","bool":true},{"option":"Embryoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Trophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Cytotrophoblast","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A zygote undergoes which of the following mechanisms after fertilization?","answers":[{"option":"Blastocyst formation","bool":false},{"option":"Neurulation","bool":false},{"option":"Cleavage formation","bool":true},{"option":"Gastrulation","bool":false},{"option":"Implantation","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following is not classified as a structural chromosomal abnormality?","answers":[{"option":"Inversion","bool":false},{"option":"Insertion","bool":false},{"option":"Deletion","bool":false},{"option":"Translocation","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A first-year medical student was observing the metaphase of meiosis. How can he differentiate it from the metaphase of mitosis?","answers":[{"option":"Reformation of nuclear membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Disappearance of nuclear membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Division of cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Homologous pairing","bool":true},{"option":"Replication","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following structure forms the skeleton of the fetus?","answers":[{"option":"Compact bone","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrocartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy bone","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"Elastic cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During observing an embryological OSPE exam, the student identifies the process of gastrulation. Which process marks its commencement?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiogenic area","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Primitive streak","bool":true},{"option":"Neural tube","bool":false},{"option":"Prechordal plate","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following hormone acts on the endometrium during the luteal phase of the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Androgen","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"The hormone responsible for the development of secondary sexual character in females is released and distributed from which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Corona radiata","bool":false},{"option":"Cumulus oophorous","bool":false},{"option":"Theca cells of growing follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":true},{"option":"Antrum","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Sensory nerve signals from the moving parts apprise the brain of whether the movement is performed correctly. If not, the brain corrects it the next time movement is required. What is the name of this process?","answers":[{"option":"Stimulus enhancement","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid feedback mechanism","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid negative feedback mechanism","bool":false},{"option":"Positive feedback mechanism","bool":false},{"option":"Adaptive control","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During a marathon race of 10km distance, an athlete requires which of the following organelles abundantly in muscle fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Vesicles with glycogen","bool":false},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxisome","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondria","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A person consumes alcohol in high quantity. Which of the following organelles are active in the liver to combat the toxic effect of the alcohol?","answers":[{"option":"Peroxisome","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Myocardial ischemia triggers coronary endothelial cells to release nitric oxide. In response, nitric oxide will activate which of the following second messenger?","answers":[{"option":"cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"DAG","bool":false},{"option":"cGMP","bool":true},{"option":"Ca","bool":false},{"option":"IP3","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A person consumes alcohol in high quantity. Which of the following organelles is active in the liver to combat the toxic effect of the alcohol?","answers":[{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxisome","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"An increase in which of the following decreases the rate of diffusion across the cell membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Lipid solubility","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration gradient","bool":false},{"option":"Thickness","bool":true},{"option":"Temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Surface area","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Sodium-potassium ATPase functions to pump the which of following ions inside and outside the cell?","answers":[{"option":"3 Na+ ions out and 2 K+ ions in","bool":true},{"option":"3 Na+ ions out and 3 K+ ions in","bool":false},{"option":"2 Na+ ions in and 3 K+ ions out","bool":false},{"option":"2 Na+ ions out and 3 K+ ions in","bool":false},{"option":"3 Na+ ions in and 2 K+ ions out","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which mucopolysaccharide accumulates due to the deficiency of iduronate sulfatase in Hunter's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaluronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Dermatan sulphate","bool":true},{"option":"Keratan sulphate","bool":false},{"option":"Chondroitin sulphate","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which type of glycosidic linkage is present in cellulose that cannot be digested with amylase present in saliva and pancreatic juice?","answers":[{"option":"Beta 1-6","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1-3","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1-4","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1-3","bool":false},{"option":"Beta 1-4","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Proteoglycans are conjugated proteins that contain carbohydrates in which form?","answers":[{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Dextran","bool":false},{"option":"Glycosaminoglycan","bool":true},{"option":"Maltotriose","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which repeating disaccharide units make the anticoagulant polymer heparin?","answers":[{"option":"N-Acetyl-D-galactosamine and  D-glucuronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"L-iduronic acid and N-acetyl galactosamine","bool":false},{"option":"N-acetyl glucosamine and D-glucuronic acid","bool":false},{"option":"D-glucosamine and L-iduronic acid","bool":true},{"option":"L-iduronic acid and N-acetyl galactosamine sulphate","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which secondary structure is characterized by a single, spiral chain of amino acids and is stabilized by hydrogen bonds?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha helix","bool":true},{"option":"Ω-loop","bool":false},{"option":"Bend","bool":false},{"option":"β-pleated sheet","bool":false},{"option":"U-turn","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which amino acid has both glucogenic and ketogenic metabolic properties?","answers":[{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"In quaternary structure, cysteine residues interact with the other polypeptide chains with the help of which of the following bonds?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrophobic interactions","bool":false},{"option":"Disulfide bridges","bool":true},{"option":"Van der Waal forces","bool":false},{"option":"Covalent interactions","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen bonding","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Emulsification of fats is a process in which large complex fat globules get converted into smaller fat molecules. Which emulsifying agent is present in the gastrointestinal tract for the digestion of fats?","answers":[{"option":"Biliverdin","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic lipase","bool":false},{"option":"Bile salts","bool":true},{"option":"Gastric lipase","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A patient came to the outpatient department with a condition that causes a dark, sometimes scaly rash to develop on skin areas exposed to sunlight. He also complained of bright redness of the tongue and constipation/diarrhea. Which deficiency causes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Thiamin","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":true},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Pantothenic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Epimers are carbohydrates that vary in one position for the placement of the OH group. Which of the following is an example of an epimer?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose and ribose","bool":false},{"option":"Mannose and ribulose","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose and fructose","bool":false},{"option":"Xylose and glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose and galactose","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following describes the process by which mRNA synthesis is initiated, elongated, and terminated?","answers":[{"option":"Translation","bool":false},{"option":"Replication","bool":false},{"option":"Splicing","bool":false},{"option":"Transcription","bool":true},{"option":"Transformation","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following is caused by the deficiency of vitamin D?","answers":[{"option":"Beriberi","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":true},{"option":"Parkinson","bool":false},{"option":"Scurvy","bool":false},{"option":"Dementia","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 20-year-old boy mistakenly infused a one-liter extra amount of 0.9% NaCl solution. What will be the intermediate effect of this infusion on his body fluid compartment?","answers":[{"option":"Decrease in ECF","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in ICF","bool":false},{"option":"ECF will remain same","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in ECF","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease in ICF","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A football player from Lyari, while playing in excessively hot weather, felt dizzy and was brought to the hospital. On examination, he was found to be dehydrated, his blood pressure was low (70/50), and his pulse rate was high (110 b/min). Which of the following explains the patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hyper osmotic volume contraction","bool":true},{"option":"Hypotonic ECF","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertonic ICF","bool":false},{"option":"Hypo osmotic volume contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Isotonic ICF","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A patient was admitted with severe substernal chest pain of 4-hour duration. His lab tests revealed an increased level of serum creatine kinase. Which of the following conditions causes this increase?","answers":[{"option":"Damage to the plasma membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Increased Golgi activity","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear lysis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Increased endoplasmic activity","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"You are asked to review a liver biopsy from a patient with a history of alcohol abuse. Which of the following pathological changes will most likely lead to the death of hepatocytes and liver cirrhosis?","answers":[{"option":"Fatty changes in liver cells","bool":false},{"option":"Karyolysis in hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Bridging necrosis in hepatocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Hydropic change of hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen deposition in hepatocyte nuclei","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A patient suffers a stroke and has left-sided weakness and paralysis in the upper extremity. Which type of necrosis is associated with a well-developed infarct of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Liquefactive","bool":true},{"option":"Enzymatic fat","bool":false},{"option":"Gangrenous","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Enveloped viruses are sensitive to desiccation and are mostly transmitted through the body fluids. From where do these viruses derive their envelopes from?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Lysosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosomes","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Some viruses are defective and need another virus to help replicate. Which of the following is an example of these viruses?","answers":[{"option":"Influenza","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis D","bool":true},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding metastatic calcification?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondria is involved in early stages","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in thyroid papilloma","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium level is normal","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in dead and dying tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Occurs in damaged heart valves","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Regarding apoptosis which pair is matched correctly?","answers":[{"option":"BH1-3 proteins - trigger apoptosis","bool":true},{"option":"RAS gene - activates apoptosis","bool":false},{"option":"BH1-4 proteins - trigger apoptosis 3","bool":false},{"option":"BH3 only proteins - inhibitors of apoptosis","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic pathway - activates caspases 8 and 10","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is it called when a specific infection is persistent, usually at a low level in a certain geographical area?","answers":[{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"High infective region","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Toxic shock syndrome caused by exotoxin directly binds to class II MHC protein and T-cell receptor. Which of the following organisms is responsible for this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus saprophyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus haemolyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Through which of the following ways are gastrointestinal tract diseases commonly transmitted in a human?","answers":[{"option":"Food or water","bool":true},{"option":"Direct human to human contact","bool":false},{"option":"Trans placental","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect human to human contact","bool":false},{"option":"Blood borne","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following statements best corresponds to transposons?","answers":[{"option":"Short sequences of transfer RNA required for mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Required for enzyme degradation during replication","bool":false},{"option":"Short sequences of DNA contain mutation genes","bool":false},{"option":"Short sequences of DNA contain regulatory genes","bool":false},{"option":"Short sequences of DNA contain antibiotic-resistant genes","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which plasmid makes the bacterial cell develop resistance against some specific antibiotics?","answers":[{"option":"Col plasmid","bool":false},{"option":"F plasmid","bool":false},{"option":"Degradative plasmid","bool":false},{"option":"R plasmid","bool":true},{"option":"Virulence plasmid","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is the function of flagella in a bacterial cell?","answers":[{"option":"Locomotion","bool":true},{"option":"Reproduction","bool":false},{"option":"Acts as a sex pili","bool":false},{"option":"Thrive in nutrient agar","bool":false},{"option":"Adhere to tissue surfaces","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"What is a cluster of polar flagella in a bacterial cell known as?","answers":[{"option":"Lophotrichous","bool":true},{"option":"Peritrichous","bool":false},{"option":"Amphitrichous","bool":false},{"option":"Monotrichous","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar flagella","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Decrease in which of the following increases the fluidity of the cell membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingosine","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrates","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A 45-year-old patient is being administered a drug through a route that offers the most first-pass metabolism. Through which route is the drug most likely being administered?","answers":[{"option":"Oral","bool":true},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Rectal","bool":false},{"option":"Inhalation","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A patient is given drug X to decrease the toxicity of heavy metal by directly binding to it and not allowing it to bind to tissues. Which of the following is an example of this kind of antagonism?","answers":[{"option":"Functional","bool":false},{"option":"Allosteric","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical","bool":true},{"option":"Irreversible","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacokinetic","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Pakistan has a three-tier healthcare system organization. The first level of care provides primary healthcare services to people. Which of the following is the component of the first level of healthcare facilities of the three-tier system?","answers":[{"option":"Informal sector","bool":false},{"option":"District headquarter hospital","bool":false},{"option":"Private general practitioner","bool":false},{"option":"Basic health unit","bool":true},{"option":"Tehsil headquarter hospital","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"What term describes any abnormality or disruption in the normal structure or function of a body part, organ, or system, which is marked by a specific set of symptoms and signs, and whose underlying cause, nature, and outcome may be identified or unknown?","answers":[{"option":"Infirmity","bool":false},{"option":"Sickness","bool":false},{"option":"Illness","bool":false},{"option":"Health","bool":false},{"option":"Disease","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"After taking a high-protein meal, which of the following cellular organelles are most active in manufacturing pepsinogen in the stomach?","answers":[{"option":"Lysosome","bool":false},{"option":"Peroxisome","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Endoplasmic reticulum","bool":true}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Intracellular Ca2+ concentration greatly impacts the force of muscular contraction. Which of the following second messenger has a role in the release of Ca2+ from the sarcoplasmic reticulum?","answers":[{"option":"Ca ions","bool":false},{"option":"IP3","bool":true},{"option":"cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"cAMP","bool":false},{"option":"DAG","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"Which of the following is the most abundant unsaturated fatty acid in membrane lipids?","answers":[{"option":"Linoleic","bool":false},{"option":"Linolenic","bool":false},{"option":"Oleic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Palmitoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A professor of public health was very popular amongst students. Her actions inspired others to dream more, learn more, do more, and become more. Which of the following best describes this definition according to John Quincy Adams?","answers":[{"option":"Manager","bool":false},{"option":"Evaluator","bool":false},{"option":"Leader","bool":true},{"option":"Teacher","bool":false},{"option":"Supervisor","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"The nurse in charge was very strict in the administration and management of her ward in the hospital. She does not hesitate to complain to higher authorities about someone making a mistake but is also quite generous when someone does a good job. In this case, the nurse in charge has what type of power over others?","answers":[{"option":"Coercive power","bool":false},{"option":"Reward power","bool":false},{"option":"Legitimate power","bool":true},{"option":"Referent power","bool":false},{"option":"Expert power","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"While dealing with a case of intellectual disability, the father of a child wanted medical treatment for the child, while the mother thought that her child was having evil spirit effects and should be treated by faith healers. Being a culturally competent doctor, how would you deal with such a situation?","answers":[{"option":"Try to convince the mother that the father is right","bool":false},{"option":"Being a culturally sensitive doctor, don't argue with them","bool":false},{"option":"Respect the cultural set values, norms, and rituals","bool":true},{"option":"Let mother take her to faith healer","bool":false},{"option":"Straightforwardly deny the understanding of the mother","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"During an awareness talk about mental health issues and their treatment,  it was highlighted that mental illness should not be stigmatized and must be treated according to ethical principles. Hence, doctors should also treat their patients without any commercial benefit from the pharmaceutical companies because of the high regard of doctors in the community. Which of the following best describes this example?","answers":[{"option":"Culture values","bool":true},{"option":"Cultural belief","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural relativism","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural norms","bool":false},{"option":"Cultural attitude","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"If red blood cells are placed in a solution containing 0.3% NaCl, what will be the effect on them?","answers":[{"option":"Swell","bool":false},{"option":"Shrink","bool":false},{"option":"Burst","bool":true},{"option":"Remain same","bool":false},{"option":"Crenate","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2023","question":"A pharmacologist invents a new drug and experiments with it on a human volunteer. What is the earliest evidence that the drug is most likely being  stored in tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Increased plasma protein bounding","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased rate of drug metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased amount of free drug excreted in the urine","bool":false},{"option":"A large volume of distribution","bool":true},{"option":"Increased number of side effects","bool":false}]}]
export default arr